<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>inspiration | Jessica Leiria Schattschneider</title>
    <link>/tag/inspiration/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/inspiration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>inspiration</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>inspiration</title>
      <link>/tag/inspiration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello Blog</title>
      <link>/post/2020-04-30-blog-reference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/post/2020-04-30-blog-reference/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div id=&#34;TOC&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-01---breake-down-the-first-barrier-and-choose-a-process-to-document&#34;&gt;Step 01 - Breake down the first barrier and choose a process to document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-02---get-inspired&#34;&gt;Step 02 - Get inspired&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to”&lt;/em&gt; posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#anchor2&#34;&gt;Personal blogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-03---find-some-paper-and-go-away-any-tech-gadgets&#34;&gt;Step 03 - Find some paper and go away any tech gadgets&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-04---identify-traps&#34;&gt;Step 04 - Identify traps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#step-05---do-what-you-love&#34;&gt;Step 05 - Do what you love&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start something new is never easy, specially if it includes turn public something we do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To finally bring this website to life, I documented the five steps I followed to do set my first professional blog, and consequently kick off the terrifying &lt;em&gt;first post&lt;/em&gt; monster. I hope that sharing my expecience can help others to win this battle too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-01---breake-down-the-first-barrier-and-choose-a-process-to-document&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step 01 - Breake down the first barrier and choose a process to document&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to make the process of start a website less painful and more productive, my initial strategy was to organized what I would have to do anyway and transform it in a post. I think that no good work is made in one day, there are always a lot of a small processes behind and the structure used to deal with this challenges can be more useful than the final result. We also tend to be better organized when we know we will present something to a public so document a process can be a good way to improve the quality of a commom process and start sharing something we put our effort on with the others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-02---get-inspired&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step 02 - Get inspired&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get inspired by others can be helpful. but it can also make you lose inside the black role of procrastination. My way to avoid this endless trap was to permit myself to get lost on the unproductive/addictive loop of google searches, tutorials and critical looks to several data scientist blogs for two days (ok, maybe three).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During this process I found easier to clusters my inspirational websites into two groups:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to”&lt;/em&gt; posts - Articles on how to organize and start a professional website. Jump to &lt;a href=&#34;#anchor&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to”&lt;/em&gt; posts&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Personal blogs - with inspirational design and content. Jump to &lt;a href=&#34;#anchor2&#34;&gt;Personal blogs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a world of fantastic blogs and tutorial out there but to avoid being overwhelmed I limit each of these two cluster on a list of five references.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;anchor&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;em&gt;“How to”&lt;/em&gt; posts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dsquintana.blog/free-website-in-r-easy/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.dsquintana.blog/free-website-in-r-easy/&lt;/a&gt; This is an incredibly easy-to-follow tutorial showing how simple it can be to set a website using R.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://news.codecademy.com/how-to-build-a-data-science-portfolio/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://news.codecademy.com/how-to-build-a-data-science-portfolio/&lt;/a&gt; Good tips about how to build a professional portfolio, specialy the section of open dataset for data science projects.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/one-datum-at-a-time/how-to-construct-a-data-science-portfolio-from-scratch-de0b70e58bc1&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://medium.com/one-datum-at-a-time/how-to-construct-a-data-science-portfolio-from-scratch-de0b70e58bc1&lt;/a&gt; A mix of personal testemonial and tips of build a good data science portfolio.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://towardsdatascience.com/how-to-build-a-data-science-portfolio-5f566517c79c&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://towardsdatascience.com/how-to-build-a-data-science-portfolio-5f566517c79c&lt;/a&gt; Highlights the importance of having a portfolio bringing real numbers and facts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;anchor2&#34; class=&#34;section level2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Personal blogs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol style=&#34;list-style-type: decimal&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/one-datum-at-a-time&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://medium.com/one-datum-at-a-time&lt;/a&gt; Excellent blog showing in practice how to start a professional web page at first time.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hansenjohnson.org/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://hansenjohnson.org/&lt;/a&gt; Mix of research with technical tool. Focused on oceanographic data, animal behaviour and spatial representation. Clean design.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://semba-blog.netlify.app/about/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://semba-blog.netlify.app/about/&lt;/a&gt; Apply different R libraries to process physical oceanographic data. Easy to follow tutorials and exciting data visualisations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mappinglab.me/#&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://www.mappinglab.me/#&lt;/a&gt; Map Design, data analysis to improve complex strategic plans in Brazil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://anitagraser.com/about/&#34; class=&#34;uri&#34;&gt;https://anitagraser.com/about/&lt;/a&gt; Movement data and spatiotemporal visualisation using QGIS and PyQGIS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-03---find-some-paper-and-go-away-any-tech-gadgets&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step 03 - Find some paper and go away any tech gadgets&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leave the computer and &lt;em&gt;digest&lt;/em&gt; all hour spend looking posts and references. Decide what is good and what works for you, for example, I prefer brief and clean posts and few menus as I easily get lost with extra distractions and paths. Visualisation can help here, a piece of paper and a pen can be the best friends to nail this step and get out of it with the best design that works for you. It can also help to keep basic standards and avoid getting lost with all the possible widgets discovered during &lt;a href=&#34;#anchor&#34;&gt;Step 02&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-04---identify-traps&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step 04 - Identify traps&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But if is it not a good idea? Are my english skills good enough? And if the project is not perfect?
A lot of questions can come specially during &lt;a href=&#34;#anchor&#34;&gt;Step 03&lt;/a&gt; but most of them are more than simple questions, they are traps. Comparison, excuses and the felling of “not good enough” can destroy a brave initiative of starting something new. Pass through this traps is never easy, but while identify them is half of the way, find the right tool to get rid of these anoying set backs can put quick end in this step and make the journey much more fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;step-05---do-what-you-love&#34; class=&#34;section level1&#34;&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Step 05 - Do what you love&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring your passion to the process. In my case, I know I love open data science, R and learn something new through coding. I also knew that I have no interest in loosing hours draging boxes and choosing color themes. My strategy in was &lt;em&gt;cheat&lt;/em&gt; my brain and put my project of lauching my first website to a friendly interface (RStudio in my case) so the process would fell as any other coding day of my life. The choice of using a platform that I was already comfortable and that would give me the control of all my and give me the opportunity to finally start to use Rmarkdown to my writings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;bring to a friendly interface - RSTUDIO
have the control
be open
learn - improve my skills in other language and with technical writing, git
share
read&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
